Mark Anthony Rathbone

Contact Details

PHONE NUMBER

+447984 682775

EMAIL ADDRESS

MarkAnthonyRathbone@gmail.com

WEBSITES

LINKEDIN / GITHUB

MARKRATHBONE.UK



Summary

I am an AWS and Microsoft Certified Cloud Practitioner. In addition, I am also a CompTIA A+ Certified IT Technician, and I have 8 years of experience with tech troubleshooting and problem solving.

Last year I completed the AWS re/Start programme run by Generation. During this course I studied Linux, Shell, Networking, Security, Python. I also learnt about the monitoring, support, and application of AWS services in Cloud environments. After this training course I successfully passed the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner exam. Since, I have continued to self-study and have covered topics such as Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform and Ansible. I also recently passed the Microsoft Azure Fundamentals exam.

My previous experiences have equipped me with a range of technical skills in both physical and cloud environments. By working in customer facing roles I have become proficient in problem-solving under pressure and communicating with a varied audience. In my next role I am looking to begin working in a Cloud environment so I can put my new skills to the test, and continue to learn and develop.

Key Skills

Communication

Time Management

Teamwork

Growth Mindset

Persistence

Personal Responsibility

Work History

JUNIOR CLOUD ENGINEER, TRANSACTTS

February 2021 → Present

At Transactts I am studying for the AWS Certified Solutions Architect certification, while shadowing the internal technical teams and learning the internal processes.

AWS RE/START, GENERATION UK&I

June 2020 → February 2021

This 12 week full time programme covered classroom-based skills development and training on IT

fundamentals. During the course I covered Linux, Python and Shell, in addition to AWS. This included learning about and becoming familiar with the monitoring and support of AWS and how to apply these services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53. Finally, during this programme I also developed my professional skills, resulting in improvements to my verbal and written communication. I also gained experience of explaining technical information and terminology to non technical end users.

RETAIL STAFF, FAST CAR DIRECT

October 2017 → May 2018

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ASSISTANT, MULTIMEDIA INTERNET CAFÉ

August 2009 → October 2017

Education & Certifications

CERTIFICATIONS (YOUR ACCLAIM)

2020

Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS re/Start Graduate

2018

CompTIA A+ ce Certification

HEATH PARK BUSINESS & ENTERPRISE COLLEGE

2007 - 2009

GCSE in Mathematics - Grade A

GCSE in English – Grade B

GCSE in Applied Science – Grade B

OCR Level 2 National Award in ICT – Pass

BTEC First Certificate in Business Studies – Merit

BTEC First Diploma in Art and Design – Merit

References available On Request